(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
POL ROCK 2024
OMARU POLKA
hololive 5th Generation
POL ROCK 2024
Polka Birthday LIVE
January 30
In hololive Live Stage
見に来てくれてありがとう！
Thanks for coming to see me!
最初は、この一曲目から始めます。
First, I'll start with this first song.
Catch the Moment!
Catch the Moment
作詞: LiSA 作曲: 田淵智也
Lyrics: LiSA Composition: Tomoya Tabuchi
そっと吐き出したため息を吸い込んだ
I inhaled the sigh I softly breathed out
後悔は 苦い味残して
Regret leaves a bitter taste behind
いつもなんで 肝心なこと言えないまま
Why do I always leave the important things unsaid?
次の 朝が顔出して
The next morning shows its face
LIVE GUEST:
KUREIJI OLLIE, MORI CALLIOPE,
OURO KRONII, HAKOS BAELZ
嫌になった運命をナイフで切り刻んで
I'll carve up the fate I've come to hate with a knife
もう一度 やり直したら
If I were to start all over again
君に出会えないかも
I might not be able to meet you
僕の声が響いた瞬間に始まる
It starts the moment my voice resonates
命のリミット 心臓がカウントしてる
The limit of life, my heart is counting down
叶えても 叶えても 終わらない願い
Even if fulfilled, a wish that never ends
汗をかいて走った 世界の秒針は
Sweating as I ran, the world's second hand
いつか止まった 僕を置いていく
Will one day leave behind the me that stopped
あと何回君と笑えるの？
How many more times can I laugh with you?
試してるんだ僕を Catch the moment
It's testing me, catch the moment
一個ずつ幸せを数える旅に
Every time I count each piece of happiness
変わっていく 未来に怯えてしまうけど
I get scared of the changing future, but...
愛情の種を大切に育てよう
Let's carefully nurture the seeds of affection
分厚い雲もやがて突き破るから
Because even thick clouds will eventually be broken through
君の声が響いた 僕らの精神が
Your voice resonated, our spirits...
呼んでいる 心臓のドアをノックしてる
...are calling, knocking on the door of the heart
臆病でも開けちゃうんだよ 信じたいから
I'll open it even if I'm a coward, because I want to believe
何も無いと思った 足元に咲いた
I thought there was nothing, but blooming at my feet...
深く確かな 根をはやす
...is a deep and certain root growing
嵐の夜が来たとしても
Even if a stormy night comes
揺らいだりはしない
I won't waver
何度でも追いついたり 追い越したり
Catching up or overtaking again and again
君が不意に分からなくなって
Suddenly I stop understanding you
息をしたタイミングが合うだけで
Just when our breathing timings match...
嬉しくなったりして
...I start feeling happy
集めた1秒を 永遠にして
Make the gathered seconds eternal
行けるんだ
I can go on
僕の声が響いた瞬間に始まる
It starts the moment my voice resonates
命のリミット 心臓がカウントしてる
The limit of life, my heart is counting down
叶えても 叶えても 終わらない願い
Even if fulfilled, a wish that never ends
汗をかいて
Sweating,
走った
I ran.
世界の秒針がいま
The world's second hand
止まった
has now stopped,
僕を置いてゆく
leaving me behind.
あと何回
How many more times
君と笑えるの
can I laugh with you?
試してるんだ僕を
It's testing me,
Catch the Moment
逃さないよ僕は
I won't let it slip away,
この時を掴め
I'll seize this moment.
Catch the Moment
ありがとう！
Thank you!
今日は楽しんでいってね！
Please enjoy yourselves today!
はい！はい！はい！はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
どうも皆さん！
Hello, everyone!
ゴーストルール、決めちゃいます。
We're going to rock 'Ghost Rule'.
最初のゲスト、ハコス・ベールズ！
My first guest, Hakos Baelz!
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you for having me!
ゴーストルール
Ghost Rule
どうだっていい言動を
Actions and words that don't matter,
嘘で吐き戻せない
I can't take them back with lies.
時効なんてやってこない
The statute of limitations never comes.
奪ったように奪われて
Being robbed just as I have robbed.
今日だって叶わない
Even today, it won't come true.
思ったように騙せない
I can't deceive as I intended.
腐っている僕には
To a rotten person like me,
腐ったものがわからない
I can't recognize what's rotten.
おいで
Come here,
ここまで
all the way here.
ステイ
Stay.
隠してしまったんだ
I ended up hiding it.
メーデー 僕と判っても
Mayday, even if you realize it's me,
もう抱きしめなくていいんだよ
you don't have to hold me anymore.
メーデー 僕が解ったら
Mayday, if you understand me,
もう一度笑ってくれるかな
will you smile for me once more?
羨望を
Envy,
まだ待っていたしるんだよ
I'm still waiting for it.
戦場を
Battlefield,
嘘つきだしているんだよ ねえ
I'm lying through my teeth, hey.
No だって言うはずが
I was supposed to say 'No',
今日だって Yes を声に出す
but today again, I voice a 'Yes'.
後悔の静寂は
In the silence of regret,
騙した方が正義なの
the one who deceives is 'justice'.
卑怯だって構わない
I don't care if I'm a coward.
祈っておいてそれはない
After praying, that's just wrong.
飾っていた情熱が
The passion I put on display
負け犬だって吠える様
howls like a loser.
おいで
Come here,
どこまで
how far?
グレイ
Grey.
被害者面したって
Even if I act like the victim,
メーデー 僕を叱ってよ
Mayday, scold me.
正直者が夢見たいなら
If an honest person wants to dream,
メーデー 僕を裁いてよ
Mayday, judge me.
最後まで甘えちまうのは
The one who depends on others until the end is—
羨望を
Envy,
まだ待っていたしるんだよ
I'm still waiting for it.
戦場を
Battlefield,
空を待っているんだよねえ
I'm waiting for the sky, hey.
足りないものを望んだら
If I wish for what I'm lacking,
僕じゃない僕に出会ってよ
meet the 'me' that isn't 'me'.
それでも前に進んだの
Even so, I moved forward.
クラクラしちゃうよもう
I'm already feeling dizzy.
足りない僕を愛してよ
Love the incomplete me.
エゴママな僕を育てたの
You raised the selfish me.
君には僕が見えるかな
I wonder if you can see me,
孤独なピエロが
the lonely clown.
メーデー 僕と判っても
Mayday, even if you realize it's me,
もう抱きしめなくていいんだよ
you don't have to hold me anymore.
メーデー 僕が解ったら
Mayday, if you understand me,
もう一度笑ってくれるかな
will you smile for me once more?
メーデー 僕を叱ってよ
Mayday, scold me.
正直者が夢見たいなら
If an honest person wants to dream,
メーデー 僕を裁いてよ
Mayday, judge me.
最後まで甘えちまうのは
The one who depends on others until the end is—
メーデー 僕を暴いてよ
Mayday, expose me.
もう時期終わるこの世界から
From this world that will soon end,
メーデー 僕と踊ってよ
Mayday, dance with me.
最初からいないと解ってた
I knew you weren't here from the start.
羨望を
Envy,
まだ待っていたしるんだよ
I'm still waiting for it.
戦場を
Battlefield,
嘘つきだしているんだよ
I'm lying through my teeth.
羨望を
Envy,
空を待っているんだよ
I'm waiting for the sky.
戦場を
Battlefield,
空を待っているんだよ
I'm waiting for the sky.
どうだっていい言動を
Actions and words that don't matter,
嘘で吐き戻せない
I can't take them back with lies.
時効なんてやってこない
The statute of limitations never comes.
奪ったように奪われて
Being robbed just as I have robbed.
ヒバナ！
Hibana!
ヒバナ
Hibana
With Baelz! 1, 2, High, High, High! One more time! High, High, High!
コンコン優しくノックして
Knock knock, knock gently,
乗り込め 心の奪還戦
and launch a battle to reclaim the heart.
妄想ばかりがフラッシュして
Delusions keep flashing by,
加速するパルス 答えはどこですか
an accelerating pulse—where is the answer?
さあ 剥き出しになって
Come now, lay yourself bare,
くだらない...
it's worthless...
...そうで　チュウ　待って
...and wait for a kiss
冗談　ばかりね　愛はない
Nothing but jokes, there is no love
壊せない壁が　キスを迫るでしょう
The unbreakable wall will force a kiss, right?
アイヤ　そんなわけないや
Aiya, that's not how it is
アイヤ　勝てばいいでしょう
Aiya, it's fine as long as I win, right?
その頭　撃ち抜いて
Shoot right through that head
終わんない愛を　愛したくないの
I don't want to love an unending love
もっとちゃんと不安にしてよ
Make me more properly anxious
いないいないばあで　演じて欲しいの
I want you to act like you're playing peek-a-boo
もっとちゃんと応えてよ
Answer me more properly
未完成だって　何度でも言うんだ
I'll say it again and again, even if it's incomplete
脳から舞台の中まで
From my brain to the stage
トントンこれで　おあいこって
Knock knock, now we're even
埋まらない時に籠もっちゃって
When it won't be filled, I hide away
完全主義は　スモーキーに
Perfectionism turns smoky
谺する声に　眩暈ともっともっと
With an echoing voice, dizziness, more and more
Knock-knock, let me go in and get the ace
You pay the face but tears don't feel the same
Now heart's for you, what's the end of this game?
You better give up and throw your every bubble away
アイヤ　こっちも選んで
Aiya, choose this one too
アイヤ　どっちも壊して
Aiya, break them both
心の根を　引き抜いて
Pull out the roots of my heart
不甲斐ない愛を　愛したくないの
I don't want to love a pathetic love
もっとちゃんと痛くしてよ
Make it more properly painful
笑えないくらいが　きっと楽しいの
It's surely fun when you can't even laugh
もっとちゃんと溶かしてよ
Melt it more properly
未完成だって　何度でも言うんだ
I'll say it again and again, even if it's incomplete
脳から舞台の中まで
From my brain to the stage
Clap!
アイヤ　そんなわけないや
Aiya, that's not how it is
アイヤ　勝てばいいでしょう
Aiya, it's fine as long as I win, right?
その頭　撃ち抜いて
Shoot right through that head
撃ち抜いて
Shoot through it
終わんない愛を　愛したくないの
I don't want to love an unending love
もっとちゃんと不安にしてよ
Make me more properly anxious
いないいないばあで　演じて欲しいの
I want you to act like you're playing peek-a-boo
もっとちゃんと応えてよ
Answer me more properly
未完成だって　何度でも言うんだ
I'll say it again and again, even if it's incomplete
脳から舞台の中まで
From my brain to the stage
不甲斐ない愛を　愛したくないの
I don't want to love a pathetic love
もっとちゃんと痛くしてよ
Make it more properly painful
笑えないくらいが　きっと楽しいの
It's surely fun when you can't even laugh
もっとちゃんと溶かしてよ
Melt it more properly
未完成だって　何度でも言うんだ
I'll say it again and again, even if it's incomplete
脳から舞台の中まで
From my brain to the stage
Alright! Let's go!
Yo-hoshki! 盛り上がっていくぜ！
Yo-hoshki! Let's get hyped!
さあ　自問自答　番狂わせ
Now, self-questioning, an upset
テレキャスター背負ったサブカルボーイが　バンカラの構え
A subculture boy with a Telecaster takes a punk-rock stance
アドレナリン　四六時中
Adrenaline 24/7
対バンには　エフェクターボード
An effects board for the gig
人見知り宣言で逃げるキッカボーイ
Kikka-boy fleeing with a declaration of social anxiety
You tell　坊ちゃん　お嬢ちゃん
You tell them, young master and young lady
お金も才能もなまじっかあるだけ　厄介だね
A nuisance to have just a bit of money and talent
Boys be ambitious (Hai hai)
Boys be ambitious (Yeah, yeah)
長い　前髪で　君　誰の　信者？
With those long bangs, whose follower are you?
信者
Follower
勘違いすんな　教祖はお前だ
Don't misunderstand, the cult leader is you!
ロキロキの　ロックンロックンロール
Roki-roki rock 'n rock 'n roll
かき鳴らす　エレクトリックギターは　Don't stop! Don't stop!
Electric guitar strumming, don't stop! Don't stop!
さあ　君の　すべてを　曝け出してみろよ
Now, go ahead and show me everything you've got
ロキロキの　ロックンロックンロール
Roki-roki rock 'n rock 'n roll
さあ　二進一退　息吐いてる？
Now, back and forth, are you breathing?
同調増えてる？
Is the agreement increasing?
知名度はあるけど人気はそんなにないから　色々大変ですね
You're known but not that popular, so it's tough, huh?
はっきり言うなよ　匿名アイコン
Don't be so blunt, anonymous icon
はっきり見せない　実写のアイコン
You don't show it clearly, real-life icon
いい歳こいて　自意識マッハボーイ
At your age, self-consciousness Mach Boy
ぶっちゃけどんだけ賢くあざとくやったって
Honestly, no matter how smartly or slyly you do it
10年後メイクは落ちてんだよ
In ten years, your makeup will have faded
Boys be ambitious (Hai hai)
Boys be ambitious (Yeah, yeah)
Like this old man
生き抜くためだ　決めろテイクアセルフ
It's for survival, decide on a selfie
Selfie!
死ぬんじゃねえぞ　お互いにな
Don't die on me, both of us
ロキロキの　ロックンロックンロール
Roki-roki rock 'n rock 'n roll
Knock Knock Knock
薄っぺら居脱ぐでもいい
Stripping off your shallowness is fine,
DANCE DANCE DANCE
さぁ目の前 あの子を
Now, shoot that girl
撃ち抜いて見せろよ
right in front of you.
ドキドキ Knock Knock Knock
Heart pounding, Knock Knock Knock
五臓六腑 ステージじゃ満足できない
My viscera aren't satisfied with just the stage.
死自由に運ばせてろ
Let me carry it on with deathly freedom.
ど、ど、ど足踏み 足踏み
Stamp, stamp, stamp your feet.
プレッシャーでいっぱい
I'm filled with pressure.
血染めのカラー 弾ませて見せろ
Let your blood-stained colors bounce.
Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha!
はー
*Sigh*
根比べは寝ていえ BABY
Tell your test of endurance to go to sleep, baby.
BABY BABY BABY BABY BABY BABY
死ぬんじゃねぇぞ
Don't you dare die.
高鳴り鳴らせ
Let your heart throb aloud.
Knock Knock Knock
今覚醒 ブリキギターは
Awakening now, the tin guitar is
DANCE DANCE DANCE
さぁ君の全てを
Now, show me
曝け出してみせろよ
everything that you are.
ドキドキ Knock Knock Knock
Heart pounding, Knock Knock Knock
Knock Knock Knock
死ぬんじゃねぇぞ
Don't you dare die.
死にたかねぇのさ
I don't wanna die.
高鳴るままに！
Just as my heart throbs!
K-U-R-E-I-J-I O-L-L-I-E!
なに？もうゾンビじゃん！
What? You're a zombie already!
んー、あ、ほらやん！
Nn, ah, look at that!
インフェルノ / 作詞・作曲: 大森元貴
Inferno / Lyrics & Music: Motoki Ohmori
照らすは闇 僕らは
Illuminating the darkness, we have
歩き慣れてきた日々も淘汰
also culled the days we've grown used to walking.
夢は安泰な暮らしだが
Our dream is a stable life, but
刺激不足故にタラタラ
we're sluggish due to a lack of stimulation.
照らすは闇 僕らの
Illuminating the darkness, where is
歩き慣れていた道はどこだ
the path we were used to walking?
時はたまに癪だが
Time is occasionally annoying, but
温もりに包まれ只
we're simply wrapped in warmth.
炎が立つ 導の方へ
Flames rise toward the guidance.
思い出すは優しいメロディー
Remembering a gentle melody.
永遠は無いんだと
They say eternity doesn't exist,
ないんだと言う
doesn't exist.
それもまたいいんだと
I'll try to smile
笑ってみる
and say that's fine too.
輝けばいつか
If we shine, someday
揺らぎも消えて
the flickering will disappear.
僕らは 命の火が
We will walk until the day
消えるその日まで歩いてゆく
the fire of our lives goes out.
ところで何故 僕らは
By the way, why have we
思考を急に止めているんだ
suddenly stopped thinking?
夢は安泰な暮らしだが
Our dream is a stable life, but
知識不足故にハラハラ
we're nervous due to a lack of knowledge.
食せば闇 夜風に
Eating the darkness, we rot away
縋り付いたまま朽ちてゆくんだ
while clinging to the night breeze.
ここは業火の中だが
We're in the middle of a hellfire, but
傷跡はヒリつき只
our scars are simply stinging.
水面が立つ 光の方へ
The water surface rises toward the light.
手を取るのは新しいメモリー
Taking a new memory by the hand.
夜空が立つ 導の方へ
The night sky rises toward the guidance.
遮るはまた 苦しいセオリー
A painful theory blocks us again.
永遠は無いんだと
They say eternity doesn't exist,
ないんだと言う
doesn't exist.
やけに虚しいんだと
I'll try to ask
問い掛けてみる
if it's awfully empty.
いつか 芝生も枯れて
Someday, even the grass will wither.
僕らは 命の泉を
We will protect and connect
守り続けて繋いでゆく
the spring of life.
学びきれずに卒業
Graduation without fully learning.
伝えきれずに失恋
Heartbreak without fully conveying.
遊びきれずに決別
Farewell without fully playing.
悟るにはまだ早い
It's too early to be enlightened.
地獄じゃあるまいし
It's not like this is hell.
躍らせる火の粉も
The sparks that make us dance,
痛みを飛ばす魔法も
the magic that flies away the pain.
全部僕の手の平の上
It's all in the palm of my hand.
永遠は無いんだと
They say eternity doesn't exist,
ないんだと言う
doesn't exist.
僕ら...
We...
フラワー
Flower
一途の火が
The fire of a single life
消えるその日まで歩いて行く
I'll keep walking until the day it goes out
半端なら K.O.
If it's half-baked, it's a K.O.
ふわふわしたいならどうぞ
If you want to feel fluffy, go ahead
開演準備しちゃおうか
Shall we get ready for the show?
泣いても笑っても愛してね
Whether you cry or laugh, love me, okay?
ほら、せーの
Now, ready, set—
手拍子響かせろ
Make the clapping resound!
Here we go!
何だかんだ言わない事もあるでしょ
There are some things you just don't say, right?
踊り踊り踊れ
Dance, dance, dance
嫌んなっちゃって泥にバカ面だろうが
Even if you're fed up and have a stupid face in the mud
溺れて落ちてね
Please drown and fall
さあ、どうだい？
Now, how is it?
もっと頑張って
Work a little harder
我儘もっと頑張って
Work a little harder on your selfishness
繋がる一人より倍増えたら
If we double from one person connected
安全牌じゃないわ
It's no longer safe
Alright 任せて ドンマイ
Alright, leave it to me, don't mind
目合ったらみんなで乗っちゃえば？
If our eyes meet, why don't we all jump on?
案外、絶好調いけそうじゃん？
Unexpectedly, it looks like we're in top form, right?
半端なら K.O.
If it's half-baked, it's a K.O.
ふわふわしたいならどうぞ
If you want to feel fluffy, go ahead
開演準備しちゃおうか
Shall we get ready for the show?
泣いても笑っても愛してね
Whether you cry or laugh, love me, okay?
ほら、せーの
Now, ready, set—
手拍子響かせろ
Make the clapping resound!
Yeah yeah yeah yeah!
これは Party!
This is a party!
Wow wow wow wow
踊り出せ 踊り出せ
Start dancing, start dancing
孤独は置いてまいれ
Leave your loneliness behind
Wow wow wow wow
痛みまで お裾分け
I'll even share my pain
今夜はバイバイ最後
Tonight is the last goodbye
どうなれ？
What'll happen?
等閑 どんな今日だい？
Neglected, how's today going?
化粧バッチリ 最高で突っ込んでしまっちゃうでしょう
With perfect makeup, we'll dive in at our best
Oh yeah!
Up & Down な テンション お手元はこちらですよ
Up & Down tension, keep your hands right here
どばっと吹き出すのは 本音の独り言
What bursts out are my true inner thoughts
別に興味ない（ない）
I'm not particularly interested (no)
特に関係ない（ないない）
It doesn't really matter (no no no)
塞ぎ込んで 絶好調 いけそうじゃん？
Shutting it in, we look like we're in top form, right?
合図を奏でて プレイヤー ほら集まって 夜更かしだ
Players, play the signal, come gather around, it's a late night
泣いていこう
Let's go on crying
パラッパパパラッパ...
Parappa-pa-parappa...
半端なら K.O.
If it's half-baked, it's a K.O.
Wow wow wow wow
踊り出せ 踊り出せ
Start dancing, start dancing
孤独は置いてまいれ
Leave your loneliness behind
Wow wow wow wow
痛みまで お裾分け
I'll even share my pain
今夜は Party!
Tonight is a party!
Wow wow wow wow
甘い惑わしを きっと フーフー
Surely, a sweet delusion, woo-hoo!
Wow wow wow wow
誓いまで お元気で
Be well, until we meet again
今夜はバイバイ最後
Tonight is the last goodbye
オリーでした！ゲストありがとう！
That was Ollie! Thanks for being a guest!
チュラ チュラ チュラ パパパ
Chura chura chura pa-pa-pa
DISCOTHEQUE
Disco lady, Disco lady
Deep emotion, Deep emotion
カモン！
Come on!
皆、森カリオペです！
Hi everyone, I'm Mori Calliope!
ポルカ先輩、Happy Birthday!
Polka-senpai, Happy Birthday!
ラストスパート！ Let's go!
Final stretch! Let's go!
Sweetie Darling 踊りましょう
Sweetie Darling, let's dance
弾ける Pure be ready
Bursting with pure, be ready
生まれ変わって甘い夢
Reborn and having a sweet dream
そっと彩りたいの
I want to color it softly
グラマラスな唇 ピンク色のつやめくネイル
Glamorous lips, shining pink nails
ガラスの向こう側に映る
Reflected on the other side of the glass
...色の空 舞い踊れ
...dance through the colored sky
ほら 世界は変わる
Look, the world is changing
君だけの幻想を見せていたい
I want to show you your own fantasy
心の中 瞳の奥
In your heart, deep in your eyes
お傍にいてほしいよ
I want you to be by my side
次の未来を語る
Talking about the next future
My Darling ねえ ビビッと来ちゃうほど
My Darling, hey, until it sends a spark through me
ハジける Sexy feeling
A bursting sexy feeling
生まれ変わって 曖昧な夢
Reborn, an ambiguous dream
外色の空 舞い踊れ
Dance through the outer-colored sky
ほら
Look
世界は変わる
the world is changing
せーの！
One, two!
チュル チュル チュル パヤパ
Churu churu churu payapa
Sexy feeling チュ チュ チュ チュ
Sexy feeling chu chu chu chu
ドラマティックな序述
A dramatic narrative
褪せないデジャブ 見続けたくて
An unfading deja vu I want to keep seeing
カラフルなスウィート・ストーリー
A colorful sweet story
心深く刻み込む
Etching it deep into my heart
小さな闇が襲い来ても
Even if a small darkness comes to attack
恋の呪文 唱えたなら
If I chant the spell of love
そうきっと 果てない空
Then surely, the endless sky
星屑のシャワー浴びて 降り注ぐ
Raining down a shower of stardust
だから Happy station 目指して行こう
So let's head for the Happy station
Fifty-fifty 合わせて
Matching up fifty-fifty
100%以上の愛
With more than 100% love
勇気がここにあると
Knowing that courage is right here
私を想ってる
You're thinking of me
せーの！
One, two!
チュル チュル チュル パヤパ
Churu churu churu payapa
退屈でしぶと コンサバティブな自分
My boring, stubborn, conservative self
君にあるがままを 好きでいてほしいと
I want you to love me just as I am
願いは
My wish is
好きだよ
that I love you
My Darling もっと一緒に踊りましょ
My Darling, let's dance together more
Secret night 素敵な
A wonderful secret night
ラブソングのデコレーション
A love song decoration
深みのハートで 奏であわせて
Playing in harmony with deep hearts
My Darling ねえ ビビッと来ちゃうほど
My Darling, hey, until it sends a spark through me
ハジける Sexy feeling
A bursting sexy feeling
生まれ変わって 曖昧な夢
Reborn, an ambiguous dream
外色の空 舞い踊れ
Dance through the outer-colored sky
ほら 世界は変わる
Look, the world is changing
せーの！
One, two!
チュル チュル チュル パヤパ
Churu churu churu payapa
Don't stop, don't stop the music
甘美な様変わり お嫌い？
Do you dislike this sweet transformation?
Don't stop, don't stop the music
さあ 始めましょう 調子合わせて 一世の Wow!
Now let's begin, in rhythm together, one, two, Wow!
チュッチュ チュルリラ
Chu chu chururira
おマジやん ほら
Seriously, look
チュッチュ チュルリラ
Chu chu chururira
仰天のソース
An astounding source
Don't stop, don't stop the music
アンバランスなステップ 止まらない
The unbalanced steps won't stop
Don't stop, don't stop the music
かき混ぜてしまいましょう
Let's mix it all up
私はシンデレラ
I am Cinderella
鼻先 お辞儀様
A bow at the tip of the nose
十二分近づいて 運命の順番は
Coming close enough, fate's turn is
ぐるぐる回る
going round and round
そして 出番よ ほら
And now it's your turn, look
モラトリアム 酔いしれて
Indulging in this moratorium
浮世をそっと抜け出して
Slipping away from the transient world
月影 響けば 二人の ダンスフロア
If the moonlight resonates, it's our dance floor
踊り踊れ 境界線
Dance and dance, the boundary line
恋という情の真ん中で
In the middle of the emotion called love
指を結んで そっと解いて
Intertwining fingers, gently letting go
もうちょっと 夢を見せたいの Wow!
I want to show you a dream a bit longer, Wow!
チュッチュ チュルリラ
Chu chu chururira
おマジやん ほら
Seriously, look
チュッチュ チュルリラ
Chu chu chururira
仰天のソース
An astounding source
ノック ノック ノック オン ザ ハッピー
Knock knock knock on the happy
とにかく 鼓動は止まらない
Anyway, the heartbeat won't stop
One, two, three, let's go!
ダンス ダンス ダンス ダンス ザ ミュージック 刹那の愛に乗って
Dance dance dance dance the music, riding on the love of a moment
自分探しだとか
Finding oneself...
生きてく意味だとか
...the meaning of living.
あぁ 運がいいかなんて
Ah, whether I'm lucky or not...
目の前のあなたを 独り占めしたい ほんとそれだけね
I want to keep you, right in front of me, all to myself. Truly that's all.
だから見栄を投げ出して
So throw away appearances
浮き世離れとか隠し続けて
And keep hiding that you're out of this world
闇夜の先に回るわ ミラーボール
The disco ball will spin beyond the dark night
あぁ 商店街は絵空事だと
Ah, the shopping street is just a fantasy
大人の子供の真ん中で
In the middle of being an adult and a child
妙にしゃかりかまってんじゃないわ
Don't be so strangely enthusiastic
ありのまま晒してちょうだい Wow!
Please show me as you are, Wow!
特別な魔法が解けたら
When the special magic is broken
また元通り戻っていくから
Everything will return to how it was before
ほらモラトリアムやけ食らって
Look, indulge in this moratorium
不器用解く霧の中
In the mist that unravels clumsiness
もっと踊って どこで踊って
Dance more, where should we dance?
ほらモラトリアム酔いしれて
Look, get intoxicated by this moratorium
不器用外抜け出して
Break out of that clumsy outside
月が泣けば 二人のダンスフロア
If the moon cries, it's a dance floor for the two of us
踊り踊り明け境界線
Dance on, dance on, until dawn, at the boundary
恋という情の真ん中で
In the middle of this emotion called love
指を結んで 心開いて
Intertwine our fingers, open your heart
もうちょっと夢を見てたいの Wow!
I want to keep dreaming a little longer, Wow!
ダンス ダンス ダンス ダンス ザ ミュージック
Dance dance dance dance the music
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー / 作詞・作曲：kemu
Dear Doppelganger / Lyrics & Composition: kemu
どうもこんにちは君の分身です
Hello, I'm your double
何の冗談か目をこすってみる
I rub my eyes, thinking it's some kind of joke
影が二つ伸びて そしてまた幕は上がる
Two shadows stretch out, and the curtain rises again
「もう一人の自分がいたら」と
Thinking, "If only there was another me..."
そんな些細な願いが僕を呼んだのさ
Such a trivial wish is what called me out
それにガタがともう悲しく全てエンディングさ
And with a rattle, it's sadly all ending
わずか数日で結果を出すよ 今までとは段違いでしょ
I'll get results in just a few days. It's on a whole other level now, right?
ねえ このクソより大事なことがあるんだよ いいだろ？
Hey, there's something more important than this crap. Isn't that right?
家事も育児も何でもやります 僕は君の分身です
Housework, childcare, I'll do it all. I'm your double.
含み笑いで最高をゆくよ
With a chuckle, I'm going for the best
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 誰は誰 君は誰
Dear Doppelganger, who is who, who are you?
あぁ 混線しちゃって 僕は誰
Ah, it's all tangled up, who am I?
ねえ 荒らしもせずに絶望も 証名の根拠なんて何処にも
Hey, without even creating a stir or despair, there's no proof of my existence anywhere
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 誰は誰 僕は誰
Dear Doppelganger, who is who, who am I?
蝕まれた存在 異世界は気付かないままに
My eroded existence, the world remains unaware
おやすみなさい 奇跡の利権を奪い合って
Good night. Struggling for the rights to this miracle...
狂い咲いた正解を求めあげてる バッババ
Searching for the correct answer that bloomed madly. Ba-ba-ba
どこかよそが可笑しな月曜日
Monday is strange somewhere else
一つ二つと崩れ行く真実が
The truths that crumble one by one...
僕を再現する お前は一体誰だと
Reproducing me... who on earth are you?
ちょっと待って知らないよ 知りもしない言葉
Wait a minute, I don't know it. Words I don't even know.
そうやっていつのまにか影が溶け行く
And just like that, the shadow melts away
僕はなんなんだろう ねえ糞だよ返して
What am I? Hey, it's crap, give it back!
アンタなんかの席はここにはもう無くて
There's no longer a place for someone like you here
もうアナタの居場所はここには無いこと分かってるんでしょう
You realize your place is no longer here, right?
ねえ 奪われたなら奪えばいいだろ 今度はオマエの番だから
Hey, if it was stolen, just steal it back. Because this time it's your turn.
含み笑いで遺影をゆくよ
With a chuckle, I'm heading towards the funeral photo
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 誰は誰 君は誰
Dear Doppelganger, who is who, who are you?
あぁ 混線しちゃって 僕は誰
Ah, it's all tangled up, who am I?
待って それは嘘だよ 命を奪うのは一人だけ
Wait, that's a lie. Only one person can take a life.
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 誰は誰 君は誰
Dear Doppelganger, who is who, who are you?
こぼれ出した毒と 乾き果てた言い訳も
The poison that spilled out and the parched excuses too...
いいぜ 器をください
Fine, give me the vessel
狂い咲いた正解を求めあげてる バッババ
Searching for the correct answer that bloomed madly. Ba-ba-ba
それはずっと続く人の業の連鎖
It's a continuous chain of human karma.
嫌だねって許し合ってみたとて
Even if we try to forgive each other, saying "I hate it."
影でビフテキのペンキをあたしも
In the shadows, I'm painting with steak sauce too.
隠し合って生まれ変わるシミュレーション
Hiding it all, a simulation of being reborn.
僕の方がちゃんと君を生きてやるから
Because I'll live your life better than you.
君の次の誰かちゃんとそこを代わって
So make sure the person after you takes your place.
もう分かってるだろ何すればいいかさ
You already know what you have to do, right?
誰か僕に火を付けてくれ
Someone, set me on fire.
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 君は誰？
Dear Doppelganger, who are you?
あぁこんな風にさ 僕を誰？
Ah, just like this, who am I?
もう止まれないや 止まれない
I can't stop anymore, I can't stop.
どうもこんにちは 君の……
Hello there, I'm your...
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー それは僕
Dear Doppelganger, that's me.
もしもあっちがさ 僕でさ
If that one over there was me,
もうあり得ないや 罪はない
It's already impossible, there's no sin.
トキシコロジー ねえ……
Toxicology, hey...
狂った世界を染め上げるんだ
I'll dye this crazy world.
幕を上げろよ 乱反射
Raise the curtain, diffuse reflection.
どうもこんにちは 君の分身です
Hello there, I'm your alter ego.
Crow Song
作詞・作曲:麻枝准
Lyrics/Composition: Jun Maeda
背後にはシャッターの壁
Behind me is a shutter wall.
指先は鉄の匂い
My fingertips smell like iron.
進め 弾け どのみち 混むでしょう
Go forward, burst out, it'll be crowded anyway.
Find way ここから
Find way, from here.
Found out 見つける
Found out, I'll find it.
Rockを奏でろ
Play the rock.
Luckを見据えろ
Fix your eyes on luck.
行き過ぎた デキない街の中
In a city that's gone too far and can't do anything,
星空が最高のご馳走
the starry sky is the best feast.
カラスたちがカカと鳴くよ
The crows are cawing.
いつも思うよ いつ眠れるんだ
I always wonder, when can I sleep?
Find way 私も
Find way, I too.
Songを歌うよ
I'll sing a song.
Rockを響かせ
Let the rock resonate.
Crowを歌うよ
I'll sing Crow.
いつまでこんな所にいる
How long are you going to stay here?
そういう奴もいた気がする
I feel like there was someone like that.
うるさいことだけ言うのなら
If you're only going to say annoying things,
漆黒の羽にさらわれて
then be swept away by jet-black wings,
消えてくれ
and disappear.
全力でもう倒れそうだ
I'm about to collapse from exhaustion.
指もすり切れて痛い
My fingers are worn out and they hurt.
でもね やるよ 今夜も ビッグなストーリー
But you know, I'll do it, tonight too, a big story.
Find way ここから
Find way, from here.
Found out 見つける
Found out, I'll find it.
Rockを奏でろ
Play the rock.
Luckを歌うよ
I'll sing luck.
いつまでもあぁここにいるよ
I'll be here forever.
通り過ぎて行く人の中
Amidst the people passing by.
闇に閉ざされたステージで
On this stage closed in by darkness...
今希望の歌を歌うよ
...I'll sing a song of hope now.
あなただって疲れてるでしょう
You're tired too, aren't you?
その背中に持たれのけたいよ
I want to lean against your back.
こんな暗闇の中からの一歩を
Taking a step from within this darkness...
照らす光を歌う
...I'll sing of the light that shines.
その歌を
That song...
感情のピクセル
Kanjou no Pixel (The Pixels of Emotion)
作詞・作曲 岡崎体育
Lyrics/Composition by Okazaki Taiiku
重ねた手のひら　翳せばもう見えなくなる
If you hold up your overlapping palms, they'll be hidden from view.
風の色はもう見えなくなる
The color of the wind can no longer be seen.
怯えて震える体を焼き尽くしてゆく
Burning away your trembling, frightened body.
もう何もかも信じたくはない
I don't want to believe in anything anymore.
I don't feel pixel... Go back to fire.
希望を辿ったって何も変わらないよ
Even if you follow hope, nothing will change.
どうぶつさんたち大集合だわいわい
Animal friends, everyone gather round, yay yay!
おいでよ　うさぎさん　きつねさん
Come over here, bunny and fox!
たぬきさん　ゾウさん
Raccoon and elephant!
みんなで楽しく　うんぱっぱのぶんぶん
Let's all have fun, unpappa bunbun!
おなかぽんぽんぽんのやっほー
Tummy pon pon pon, yippee!
チーターさんも駆けっこじゃ負けないぞ
Cheetah-san won't lose in a race either!
過去を消し去るように走れ
Run as if to erase the past!
いくぞ！
Let's go!
Don't you fuck with me!
狂い出したイメージと
With an image that's started to go mad...
絶望の隙間に消え落ちてゆく
...it vanishes into the cracks of despair.
零れ落とした　闇雲なアンサー
The reckless answer that spilled out...
まだ見つからないまま
...remains yet to be found.
風の色はもう見えないけど
I can't see the color of the wind anymore, but...
前までは見えてた怖ぁ
...it's scary because I could see it before.
I don't feel pixel! Go back to fire!
Step on the pixel... yeah!
どうぶつさんたち大集合だわいわい
Animal friends, everyone gather round, yay yay!
おいでよ　ワニさん　仲間に入れてあげて
Come over here, alligator, let him join the group!
ワニさんを　仲間に入れてあげて
Let alligator join the group!
みんなで楽しく　うんぱっぱのぶんぶん
Let's all have fun, unpappa bunbun!
おなかぽんぽんぽんのやっほー
Tummy pon pon pon, yippee!
ワニさんも仲間にいれてあげて
Let alligator join the group too!
HORN READY!
Aaaaah!
COME ON!
分かち合えない
Unable to share...
生き物としてのカテゴリライズの壁
...the walls of categorization as creatures.
乾いた果実も
Even a dried fruit...
一度乾くともう戻れない
Once it's dried, it can never go back.
どうぶつさんたち大集合だわいわい
Animal friends, everyone gather round, yay yay!
そろそろ　ワニさんも仲間に入れてあげて
It's about time to let alligator join the group!
みんなで楽しく　うんぱっぱのぶんぶん
Let's all have fun, unpappa bunbun!
おなかぽんぽんぽんのやっほー
Tummy pon pon pon, yippee!
さすがに気の毒になってくる　思いやりという裏の冒涜的価値の再認識
As expected, it becomes pitiable. Re-recognizing the blasphemous value behind what's called "compassion".
ワニさんも仲間に入れてあげて
Let alligator join the group too!
Baby baby baby baby...
君の胸にキスをしたら
If I kiss your chest
君はどんな声出すんだろう
I wonder what kind of voice you'll make
白い幻想的な水色の水着を溶かすなよ
Don't let the white visionary light-blue swimsuit melt
君を乗せた宇宙船が
The spaceship carrying you
夕暮れの彼方へ消えて
Disappears beyond the sunset
光るプラネタリウム
The shining planetarium
いっそのこと僕を吸い込んでよ
Why don't you just suck me in?
君に彼氏がいたら悲しいけど
It'd be sad if you had a boyfriend
君が好きだと言うそれだけで
Just hearing you say you like me
僕は嬉しいのさ
Makes me so happy
幻みたいなメリーゴーランド
Like a phantom merry-go-round
一瞬が永遠に感じて
A moment feels like eternity
僕の汗の匂いが
The scent of my sweat
君にバレたような気がした
I felt like you noticed it
君に彼氏がいたら悲しいけど
It'd be sad if you had a boyfriend
君が好きだと言うそれだけで
Just hearing you say you like me
僕は嬉しいのさ
Makes me so happy
嗚呼 夢で逢えたら良いな
Ah, I hope we can meet in my dreams
君の笑顔にときめいて
Your smile makes my heart flutter
嗚呼 夢で逢えたら良いな
Ah, I hope we can meet in my dreams
夜の波を超えて行くよ
I'll cross over the waves of night
Baby baby baby baby...
君に好きな人がいたら悲しいけど
It'd be sad if you liked someone else
君を思うことがそれだけが
Thinking about you, just that
僕のすべてなのさ
Is my everything
嗚呼 夏の終わりが君をさらって行く
Ah, the end of summer is taking you away
君の香りだけを残して
Leaving only your scent behind
嗚呼 夏の終わりが君をさらって行く
Ah, the end of summer is taking you away
夜の波を超えて行くよ
I'll cross over the waves of night
嗚呼 夢で逢えたら良いな
Ah, I hope we can meet in my dreams
君の笑顔にときめいて
Your smile makes my heart flutter
嗚呼 夢で逢えたら良いな
Ah, I hope we can meet in my dreams
夜の波を超えて行くよ
I'll cross over the waves of night
Baby!
Oh yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah!
ここまで本当にありがとうございます。
Thank you so much for everything up to now.
えっと……
Um...
十分伝えられたと思うけど、
I think I've conveyed enough,
でもまだ伝えきれてません。
but I still haven't expressed it all yet.
だからね、言いたいわけですよ僕は。
So, I want to say this.
世界はそれを愛と呼ぶんだぜ！
The world calls it love!
世界はそれを愛と呼ぶんだぜ
The World Calls It Love
作詞・作曲　山口隆
Lyrics & Composition: Takashi Yamaguchi
涙の中に微かな明かりが灯ったら
When a faint light is lit within the tears
君の目の前で温めてたこと話すのさ
I'll talk about the things I've been nurturing right before your eyes
それでも僕らの声が乾いてゆくだけなら
Even so, if our voices are just going to dry up
朝が来るまでせめて誰かと歌いたいんだ
Then I want to sing with someone at least until morning comes
昨日のあなたが嘘だと言うなら
If you say that who you were yesterday was a lie
昨日の景色を捨ててしまうだけだ
Then I'll just throw away yesterday's scenery
つなぐのは新しい君と僕なのさ
What connects us is a new you and me
僕らなぜか確かめ合う
For some reason, we confirm it with each other
世界じゃそれを愛と呼ぶんだぜ
In this world, that's what they call love
心の声を つなぐのが
Connecting the voices of our hearts
これほど怖いものだとは
I didn't know it was such a scary thing
君と僕が声を合わす
You and I join our voices together
今までの過去なんてなかったかのように
As if the past up until now never even existed
歌い出すんだ
We start to sing
僕らはいつでも誰かを疑っちまうから
Because we're always doubting someone
せめて今だけ美しい歌を歌うのさ
At least for now, let's sing a beautiful song
悲しい言葉では
With sad words,
何も変わらないんだぜ
nothing is going to change
奴らが何をしたって言うんだ
What does it matter what they did?
昨日のあなたが裏切りの空なら
If your yesterday was a sky of betrayal
昨日の景色を忘れてしまうだけだ
Then I'll just forget yesterday's scenery
新しい日々を変えるのは
What changes the new days
いじらしいほどの愛なのさ
is an almost heart-wrenching love
僕らそれを確かめ合う
We confirm it with each other
世界じゃそれも愛と呼ぶんだぜ
In this world, that too is what they call love
心の声を つなぐのが
Connecting the voices of our hearts
これほど怖いものだとは
I didn't know it was such a scary thing
僕らなぜか声を合わす
For some reason, we join our voices
今までの過去なんてなかったかのように
As if the past up until now never even existed
歌い出すんだぜ
We start to sing
僕らが！ 僕らが新しい日々を想う時に、
When we! When we think of the new days,
僕らはどうしても愛という言葉を使ってしまうわけですよ！
we inevitably end up using the word 'love'!
心の声と、あなたの憎しみと裏切りを、
The voice of the heart, and your hatred and betrayal,
愛と言いたいわけですよ！
I want to call it all love!
愛！ と！
Love! And!
平！ 和！
Peace!
愛！ と！ 平！ 和！
Love! And! Peace!
悲しみで花が咲くものか！
As if flowers could bloom from sadness!
新しい日々の僕たちは、
We in our new days,
高鳴る予感がしてるのさ、君も！
are having a throbbing premonition, you too!
僕が夢を叫ぶ
I'll shout my dreams
世界はそれを愛と呼ぶんだぜ
The world calls that love
あなたの為に歌うのが
Singing for your sake is...
これほど怖いものだとは
...such a scary thing
だけど僕ら確かめ合う
But we'll confirm it with each other
今までの過去なんて
As if the past until now...
なかったかのように
...never even existed
悲しみの夜なんて
As if nights of sadness...
なかったかのように
...never even existed
歌い出すんだぜ
I'll start singing
歌い出そうぜ
Let's start singing
BABY, LOVE FOR YOU
そして本当に歌いたいことは
And what I really want to sing is...
世界はそれを愛と呼ぶんだぜ！
The world calls that love!
LOVE AND PEACE!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
LOVE AND PEACE!
はい！というわけで、改めまして尾丸ポルカです！
Alright! So, once again, I'm Omaru Polka!
ここまで駆け足で、ありがとうございました！
Thank you for joining me on this whirlwind run!
というわけで、こちらからは...えーと、これからは、これからは！
And so, from here... uh, from now on, from now on!
お決まり！誕生日記念グッズ出ますのグッズ紹介だ！ドーン！
The usual! Here's the birthday memorial goods intro! Boom!
行け、LOVE AND PEACE!
Go, LOVE AND PEACE!
LOVE AND PEACE!
誕生日記念2024 こちら、ドドドン！情報量多すぎる！
Birthday Memorial 2024. Here they are! There's so much info!
さあ、一個一個整理していこうか。
Now, let's go through them one by one.
まずはですね、こちらになっております！はい！
First up, we have this! Yes!
大迫力のポルカをお楽しみください！
Please enjoy this high-impact Polka!
フルグラフィックTシャツ出ました！
The Full Graphic T-shirt is here!
こちらですね、南野あき先生描き下ろしとなっております。
This is an original illustration by Akino Minami-sensei.
こちら、はっぴの上にですね、着るもよしでね。
You can even wear it over a happi coat.
また新しい服が増えたよ、ポルカ。
I've got more new clothes now.
クローゼットにしまっておけば、おまるぽるかをいつでも堪能できるぜって感じで。
Keep it in your closet and enjoy Omaru Polka anytime.
いいんじゃないでしょうか！そして次、こちら！
Isn't that great? And next, this!
はい、愛しくてスリムなかたちのクリアボトル！
Yes, the lovely and slim-shaped clear bottle!
あ、可愛い！これね、いつものとはちょっと違うかたちの...
Ah, cute! This is a slightly different shape than usual...
なんだろうね、スリムな、クリアな、あの四角いっぽい感じの素材になっております。
It's made of a slim, clear, square-ish material.
こちらも是非よろしくお願いいたします。
Please check this one out as well.
今日のロゴだね。続いてこちら、デデン！
It features today's logo. Next, this!
これも今日のロゴじゃい！
This one has today's logo too!
ちょっとそこまで...あ、ちょっとそこまでの方じゃなかった。
For a quick... Ah, wait, it wasn't that one.
おしゃれすぎるポルカのラバーバンド。
The incredibly stylish Polka rubber band.
バッグにね、ギュッとつけるもよし、腕にギュッとつけて現地に行くもよし。
Strap it to your bag or arm when you head to the venue.
ボタンで留められます。完璧！
It fastens with a button. Perfect!
はい、そしてこちら！これがだね！
And next is this! This is the one!
ちょっとそこまで！ポルカのミニサコッシュ。
Just a quick trip! Polka's mini sacoche.
あ、いいね！スマホとなんかちょっとお金入ればいいよねって人はこれをどうぞ。
If you just need space for a phone and some cash, this is it.
はい、今日のお土産にって感じのコーナーでした。まだまだ続きます。
That was our "souvenirs for today" corner. More to come!
そしてさらにこちら！はい、シチュエーションボイスは...
And there's even more! The situation voice is...
「本番前の作戦会議！」を僕らしましたよね、そういえばね。
We had a "pre-show strategy meeting," remember?
したよね、覚えてるかな？覚えてるね。それを勝手に録音させていただきましたっていうのは...
We did, right? I hope you remember. I recorded it secretly...
嘘で、ていう体で、はい、っていう体のシチュエーションボイスになっております！
...just kidding! It's a situation voice with that theme!
はい、それでは最後に、フルセット購入特典、こちら！
Alright, finally, the full set purchase bonus! Here!
直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカード！
Postcard with a hand-signed signature and foiled message!
そして特典、特典ボイスはまだだったね。今度は急いでしまったな。
And the bonus... I forgot the bonus voice. I rushed it.
どうしようかな、これはね、特典ボイスもあるんです、実は。見てくれ、君たち。
Actually, there's also a bonus voice. Look, everyone.
直筆サインもあれば、特典ボイスもある！
You get the signature AND a bonus voice!
「お疲れ様を伝えたくて電話」ね！
It's called "Calling to say 'good job'"
ま、今はね、ちょっと、まあそういうこともあるんだけど。
Well, for now, things like that happen.
まあね、そういうこともあるんだけど、あるんですよ、実はボイスっていうものがね。
Well, it happens, but the voice does exist.
はい、ね、あってさ、そう。素晴らしい。いや、ありがとう。
Yes, it's there. Wonderful. Thank you.
みんな、じゃあこれをね、是非このあと販売する予定なので、よろしくお願いします！
Everyone, these will be on sale after this, so please look forward to it!
はい、全ての品が揃ったということで。
Alright, now that all the items have been shown.
最後の最後に最後に最後に、もう一曲だけ歌わせてください！
At the very, very end, let me sing just one more song!
魂の響き！みんな、まだいけるか！？
The resonance of the soul! Everyone, can you keep going!?
盛り上がれるか！？聞こえてんぞ！
Can you get hyped!? I can hear you!
よろしくお願いします！はい！
Let's do this! Yes!
何回でも言います！みんな今日は本当にありがとう！
I'll say it as many times as it takes! Thank you all so much for today!
届いてますか！？
Is it reaching you!?
さあ、最後はこの曲でお別れしましょう！
Now, let's part with this final song!
シュガーソングとビターステップ！
Sugar Song and Bitter Step!
シュガーソングとビターステップ
作詞・作曲 田淵智也
Sugar Song and Bitter Step
Lyrics & Composition: Tomoya Tabuchi
イェー！
Yeah!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
超天変地異みたいな狂騒にも慣れて
Getting used to the uproar like a super natural disaster
こんな日常を平和と見間違う
Mistaking such a daily life for peace
ランブリングコースター 揺さぶられながら
Rumbling coaster, while being shaken
見失えないものはなんだ？
What is it that I can't lose sight of?
平等性原理主義の概念に飲まれて
Swallowed by the concept of equality fundamentalism
心までがまるでエトセトラ
Even my heart is like et cetera
大嫌い 大好き ちゃんと喋らなきゃ
Hate it, love it, I have to speak properly
人形とさして変わらないし
Otherwise I'm no different from a doll
宵街を行く人だかりに
In the crowd of people going through the evening streets
嬉しそうだったり 寂しそうだったり
Looking happy, or looking lonely
コントラストが五線を飛び回り
The contrast flies around the staff
歌とリズムになれば
If it becomes song and rhythm
ママレード＆シュガーソング、ピーナッツ＆ビターステップ
Marmalade & Sugar Song, Peanuts & Bitter Step
甘くて苦くて目が回りそうです
Sweet and bitter, I feel like my head is spinning
南南西を目指してパーティを続けよう
Let's keep the party going towards the south-southwest
世界中を驚かせてしまう夜になる
It will be a night that surprises the whole world
I feel 上々 連鎖になってリフレクト
I feel great, becoming a chain and reflecting
フー！
Woo!
ニッパー！
Ni-pa!
ハーイ！
Hi!
蓋然性合理主義の正論に揉まれて
Buffeted by the sound arguments of probabilistic rationalism
僕らの音楽は道具になり下がる？
Will our music degenerate into a mere tool?
こっちを向いてよ 背を向けないでよ
Look this way, don't turn your back
それは正論にならないけど
That won't become a sound argument, though
祭囃子のその後で
After the festival music
昂ぶったままの人 泣き出し出してしまう人
Those who stay excited, those who start crying
多分同じだろ
They're probably the same
でも言葉にしようもんなら
But if I were to put it into words
稚拙がきわまれり
It would be the height of childishness
最高だシュガーソング、幸せでビターステップ
It's the best, Sugar Song; feeling happy, Bitter Step
死ねない理由をそこに映し出せ
Project the reason why I can't die onto that
惜しがったって等速で明日は来ちゃうけど
Even if you regret it, tomorrow will come at the same speed
脳内天気予報のアップデートを果たしたなら
Once the internal weather forecast has been updated
フー！
Woo!
イェー！
Yeah!
フー！
Woo!
ヘーイ！
Hey!
フー！
Woo!
盛り上がってこう！
Let's get excited!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi!
いっそげー！
Hurry up!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi!
踊れー！
Dance!
Someday 狂騒が息を潜めても
Someday, even if the uproar holds its breath
Someday 正論に意味がなくなっても
Someday, even if sound arguments lose their meaning
Feeling song & step
鳴らし続けることだけが
Just continuing to make sound
僕たちを僕たちたらしめる証明になる
Will be the proof that makes us who we are
Q.E.D.!
ママレード＆シュガーソング、ピーナッツ＆ビターステップ
Marmalade & Sugar Song, Peanuts & Bitter Step
生きていく理由をそこに映し出せ
Project the reason for living onto that
北北東は後背位 その距離が誇らしい
North-north-east is the rear position, that distance is something to be proud of
世界中を驚かせ続けよう
Let's keep surprising the whole world
ママレード＆シュガーソング、ピーナッツ＆ビターステップ
Marmalade & Sugar Song, Peanuts & Bitter Step
甘くて苦くて目が回りそうです
Sweet and bitter, I feel like my head is spinning
南南西を目指してパーティを続けよう
Let's keep the party going towards the south-southwest
世界中を驚かせてしまう夜になる
It will be a night that surprises the whole world
I feel 上々 連鎖になってリフレクト
I feel great, becoming a chain and reflecting
Goes on 一石を投じては絶好
Goes on, throwing a stone and it's perfect
ハイ！
Hi!
一石を投じては絶好
Throwing a stone and it's perfect
You got happiness!
Wait with melody!
フー！
Woo!